Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪In the old house, a light breeze blows♪
♪في البيت القديم، تهب نسمة خفيفة♪
♪Carrying a wisp of floral fragrance♪
♪تحمل خصلة من العطر الزهري♪
♪You left in such haste, without hesitation♪
♪لقد غادرت على عجل، دون تردد♪
♪Before I could even feel the joy♪
♪قبل أن أشعر بالفرح♪
♪I dared not write a single word♪
♪لم أجرؤ على كتابة كلمة واحدة♪
♪Afraid it would give my heart away♪
♪أخشى أن يكشف قلبي♪
♪Leaving behind a foolish soul in loneliness♪
♪ترك وراءه روحًا حمقاء في الوحدة♪
♪The world grows old♪
♪العالم يشيخ♪
♪Time slips by like a blade♪
♪يمر الوقت مثل الشفرة♪
♪Through every day and night as I wait for the flowers to bloom♪
♪في كل يوم وليلة وأنا أنتظر الزهور لتتفتح♪
♪It feels as though a thousand years never passed♪
♪أشعر وكأن ألف عام لم تمر أبدًا♪
♪The wind lets petals fall into your palm♪
♪الريح تجعل البتلات تسقط في راحة يدك♪
♪Love makes us foolish, lost in endless memories♪
♪الحب يجعلنا حمقى، ضائعين في ذكريات لا نهاية لها♪
♪No one cares about our story♪
♪لا أحد يهتم بقصتنا♪
♪Slowly fading away♪
♪تتلاشى ببطء♪
♪Flowers bloom in snow, brief as life itself♪
♪تزهر الزهور في الثلج، قصيرة مثل الحياة نفسها♪
♪So many poems through the ages speak of♪
♪تتحدث العديد من القصائد عبر العصور عن♪
♪Love and hatred, partings and vows of the past♪
♪الحب والكراهية، الفراق وعهود الماضي♪
♪Had we never crossed paths in this lifetime♪
♪لو لم نلتقي قط في هذه الحياة♪
♪Nothing could separate us, even if we were oceans apart♪
♪لا شيء يمكن أن يفصلنا، حتى لو كنا بعيدين عن بعضنا البعض بالمحيطات♪
=The Princess Decree=
=مرسوم الأميرة=
=Episode 10=
=الحلقة 10=
(Old Bookshop)
(المكتبة القديمة)
We shouldn't stay here long.
لا ينبغي لنا البقاء هنا لفترة طويلة.
Let's talk somewhere else.
دعونا نتحدث في مكان آخر.
Go.
يذهب.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
I heard news inside Gan Sheng's residence.
سمعت أخبارًا داخل مسكن جان شنغ.
They're setting a trap to capture Mr. Qingya alive.
إنهم ينصبون فخًا للقبض على السيد تشينغيا حيًا.
I see.
أرى.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
It's dangerous for you there.
إنه أمر خطير بالنسبة لك هناك.
Be careful.
احرص.
You have shown me great kindness.
لقد أظهرت لي اللطف الكبير.
If I can serve you,
إذا كان بإمكاني خدمتك،
I'm willing to give my life.
أنا مستعد للتضحية بحياتي.
Mr. Qingya.
السيد تشينغيا.
The one who sent the letter wasn't the bookseller, but Gan Sheng.
الشخص الذي أرسل الرسالة لم يكن بائع الكتب، بل كان جان شنغ.
He set this trap
لقد وضع هذا الفخ
to ensnare you and force you into his service.
ليوقعك في الفخ ويرغمك على خدمته.
That's why
لهذا السبب
I had to
اضطررت
intercept you on the route he knew you'd take.
اعترضك على الطريق الذي كان يعلم أنك ستسلكه.
Everyone knows
الجميع يعرف
your relationship with General Gan
علاقتك بالجنرال جان
is far from ordinary.
هو بعيد كل البعد عن العادي.
If that's the case,
إذا كان الأمر كذلك،
why ruin his plan
لماذا نخرب خطته
and help me?
ومساعدتي؟
If I hadn't used the bookseller as bait,
لو لم أستخدم بائع الكتب كطعم،
you wouldn't have exposed your whereabouts
لن تكشف عن مكان وجودك
and gotten in danger.
وأصبحت في خطر.
It started because of me.
لقد بدأ الأمر بسببي.
I should take responsibility.
ينبغي لي أن أتحمل المسؤولية.
If General Gan finds out about this,
إذا علم الجنرال جان بهذا الأمر،
will it implicate you?
هل سيؤثر عليك ذلك؟
You seem concerned about my relationship with him.
يبدو أنك قلق بشأن علاقتي به.
What if
ماذا إذا
I do get implicated,
أنا متورط،
will you help me?
هل ستساعدني؟
If you have a conflict with General Gan,
إذا كان لديك صراع مع الجنرال جان،
I'll help you.
سأساعدك.
Consider it repaying today's favor.
اعتبر ذلك سدادًا لخدمة اليوم.
But
لكن
I'd rather you stay alive
أفضّل أن تبقى على قيد الحياة
and live freely.
والعيش بحرية.
Why?
لماذا؟
Because
لأن
you saved my life.
لقد انقذت حياتي.
Five years in Beijiang,
خمس سنوات في بكين،
surrounded by ice and frost.
محاطة بالجليد والصقيع.
It helped me survive.
لقد ساعدني على البقاء.
Just because my play script encouraged you.
فقط لأن نص مسرحيتي شجعك.
How does that count as saving your life?
كيف يمكن اعتبار ذلك بمثابة إنقاذ لحياتك؟
(Five Years Ago, Beijiang Military Camp)
(قبل خمس سنوات، معسكر بكين العسكري)
This is
هذا هو
Jing's Princess Royal.
الأميرة الملكية جينغ.
Look at her.
أنظر إليها.
That face
هذا الوجه
and that waist.
وهذا الخصر.
Do you like her?
هل تحبها؟
Come on, drink up.
هيا، اشرب.
Drink. Here.
اشرب. هنا.
Someone who doesn't care about living
شخص لا يهتم بالعيش
won't fear you.
لن يخاف منك.
Even if I die,
حتى لو مت،
I'll drag you down with me.
سأسحبك معي إلى الأسفل.
Princess or not,
أميرة أم لا
you're still our spoils of war.
أنت لا تزال غنائم حربنا.
♪On the sheer cliffs, snow stretches endlessly♪
♪على المنحدرات الشاهقة، يمتد الثلج إلى ما لا نهاية♪
♪A white stag treads beneath a frost-lit moon♪
♪أيّل أبيض يمشي تحت ضوء القمر المضاء بالصقيع♪
♪I once belonged to Zhaoyang Palace♪
♪كنتُ ذات يومٍ جزءًا من قصر تشاويانغ♪
♪Today, I turn into the snows of Yin Mountain♪
♪اليوم، أتحول إلى ثلوج جبل يين♪
♪Not a bride in red lamenting a distant marriage♪
♪ليست عروسًا ترتدي اللون الأحمر تندب زواجًا بعيدًا♪
♪Bear the stars and guard the frontier♪
♪تحمل النجوم وتحرس الحدود♪
♪I will go home again when spring returns♪
♪سأعود إلى المنزل مرة أخرى عندما يعود الربيع♪
I will go home again when spring returns.
سأعود إلى المنزل مرة أخرى عندما يعود الربيع.
Yes.
نعم.
Live.
يعيش.
I must live.
يجب أن أعيش.
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
I had already accepted death.
لقد قبلت الموت بالفعل.
I was only
انا كنت فقط
waiting for the right moment.
انتظار اللحظة المناسبة.
If I hadn't heard that play,
لو لم أسمع تلك المسرحية،
the person standing before you now
الشخص الذي يقف أمامك الآن
would be a wandering soul.
ستكون روحًا تائهة.
You killed my mentor
لقد قتلت مرشدي
for revenge.
للانتقام.
Did he not deserve to die?
ألم يستحق الموت؟
I suffered so much in Beijiang these past five years.
لقد عانيت كثيرًا في بكين خلال السنوات الخمس الماضية.
If not for hatred, I wouldn't have survived until now.
لو لم يكن هناك كراهية، لم أكن قد نجوت حتى الآن.
Liu Zhen was tied to it all.
وكان ليو تشن مرتبطًا بكل هذا.
(Pingning.)
(بينج)
(Which one is the real you?)
(أي واحد هو أنت الحقيقي؟)
So
لذا
how is that not saving my life?
كيف أن هذا لا ينقذ حياتي؟
Whatever it is...
مهما كان الأمر...
Thank you
شكرًا لك
for helping me today.
لمساعدتي اليوم.
I won't forget
لن انسى
this kindness.
هذا اللطف.
You just said
لقد قلت للتو
you owe me a favor.
أنت مدين لي بمعروف.
Don't forget it.
لا تنسى ذلك.
Thank you for the trouble.
شكرا لك على المتاعب.
(To General Gan)
(إلى الجنرال جان)
Mr. Qingya.
السيد تشينغيا.
Tonight's plan was ruined by Princess Royal.
لقد تم تدمير خطة الليلة من قبل الأميرة الملكية.
Looks like
يبدو مثل
you'll have to meet General Gan tomorrow instead.
سيتعين عليك مقابلة الجنرال جان غدًا بدلاً من ذلك.
Since you've already prepared a fallback,
نظرًا لأنك قمت بالفعل بإعداد خطة بديلة،
why are you
لماذا انت؟
still uneasy?
لا تزال غير مرتاحة؟
Planning is easy.
التخطيط سهل.
People's hearts are not.
قلوب الناس ليست كذلك.
When you were teaching me to play chess today,
عندما كنت تعلميني لعب الشطرنج اليوم،
you said those in the game are blind,
لقد قلت أن أولئك الموجودين في اللعبة مكفوفين،
only by stepping outside it
فقط بالخروج منه
can one see the whole board.
هل يمكن رؤية اللوحة بأكملها؟
Maybe the same applies
ربما ينطبق نفس الشيء
when judging a person.
عند الحكم على شخص ما.
Seeing Mr. Qingya
رؤية السيد تشينغيا
is truly difficult.
من الصعب حقا.
You suffered last night.
لقد عانيت الليلة الماضية.
Please.
لو سمحت.
What's the meaning of this?
ما معنى هذا؟
The place was surrounded by elite soldiers last night.
كان المكان محاطًا بجنود النخبة الليلة الماضية.
An inescapable trap.
فخ لا مفر منه.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Did you take me for a guest
هل أخذتني كضيف؟
or a fugitive?
أم هارب؟
In other words,
بعبارة أخرى،
you went there after all.
لقد ذهبت إلى هناك بعد كل شيء.
But seeing how you treated me,
ولكن عندما رأيت كيف عاملتني،
I changed my mind.
لقد غيرت رأيي.
My men acted on their own.
رجالي تصرفوا بمفردهم.
I only wanted to keep you safe.
لقد أردت فقط أن أبقيك آمنًا.
I didn't expect
لم اتوقع
to make you misunderstand instead.
لكي أجعلك تسيء الفهم بدلا من ذلك.
Are the men you replaced in this courtyard
هل الرجال الذين استبدلتهم في هذه الساحة
also here to "protect" me?
هل أنت هنا أيضًا لحمايتي؟
Indeed.
بالفعل.
I value you the most.
أنا أقدرك أكثر من أي شيء آخر.
Your safety
سلامتك
naturally comes first.
يأتي بطبيعة الحال أولاً.
I imagine you act the same way in court.
أتخيل أنك تتصرف بنفس الطريقة في المحكمة.
Even though this capital
على الرغم من أن هذه العاصمة
is already in your control,
هو بالفعل تحت سيطرتك،
you're still troubled.
مازلت مضطربًا.
These civil officials
هؤلاء المسؤولين المدنيين
would rather die than yield.
يفضل الموت على الاستسلام.
You truly are a hidden talent.
أنت حقا موهبة خفية.
Living in a humble room, yet seeing the whole world.
العيش في غرفة متواضعة، ولكن رؤية العالم أجمع.
Admirable.
رائع.
Seeing you like this,
رؤيتك هكذا،
I already understand
انا فهمت بالفعل
why the army fund reform
لماذا إصلاح صندوق الجيش
still hasn't been implemented.
لم يتم تنفيذه بعد.
Please
لو سمحت
enlighten me.
أنرني.
World affairs should be handled with openness, not with obstruction.
ينبغي التعامل مع الشؤون العالمية بانفتاح، وليس بالعرقلة.
The civil officials
المسؤولون المدنيون
are just a bunch of lousy scholars.
هم مجرد مجموعة من العلماء السيئين.
Even if they shout the loudest,
حتى لو صرخوا بأعلى صوتهم،
so what?
وماذا في ذلك؟
What truly matters
ما هو المهم حقا
is prying at the noble clans.
يتطفل على العشائر النبيلة.
If you want profit,
إذا كنت تريد الربح،
you must
يجب عليك أن
(List of Noble Clans)
(قائمة العشائر النبيلة)
give some to them first.
أعطيهم بعضًا منها أولاً.
(Suzhou Huang, Longxi Zheng, Sichuan Shen, Hedong Pei)
(سوتشو هوانغ، لونجكسي تشنغ، سيتشوان شين، هيدونغ بي)
Good.
جيد.
Excellent.
ممتاز.
As expected of you.
كما هو متوقع منك.
Would you be willing to stay,
هل ترغب في البقاء؟
advise me,
انصحني
and build something great together?
وبناء شيء عظيم معًا؟
Whatever you want,
أياً كان ما تريد،
just name it.
فقط أسميه.
Only you
أنت فقط
can give me what I want.
يمكن أن تعطيني ما أريد.
♪When we first met, moonlight rippled on the water♪
♪عندما التقينا لأول مرة، كان ضوء القمر يتلألأ على الماء♪
♪Your silhouette in dreams turning back with gentle eyes♪
♪ظلك في الأحلام تعود بعيون لطيفة♪
♪A trace upon my heart, a thought quietly hidden♪
♪أثر على قلبي، فكرة مخفية بهدوء♪
♪Words almost spoken, yet our story froze in time♪
♪الكلمات كادت أن تُقال، لكن قصتنا تجمدت في الزمن♪
♪Your gaze felt familiar♪
♪نظرتك كانت مألوفة♪
♪Etched into my heart, one tear swelling into a sea♪
♪محفورة في قلبي، دمعة واحدة تتضخم في البحر♪
♪How many times have we brushed past as our fates wavered?♪
♪كم مرة مررنا بمصيرنا عندما ترددت أقدارنا؟♪
♪Only to circle back into someone's open palm♪
♪فقط للعودة إلى راحة يد شخص ما المفتوحة♪
♪That moment I saw you, spring awakened in me♪
♪في تلك اللحظة التي رأيتك فيها، أيقظ الربيع في داخلي♪
♪My heart suddenly becomes soft and tender♪
♪قلبي فجأة يصبح رقيقًا وحنونًا♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪Smiles and tears blurred everything in the past♪
♪الابتسامات والدموع طمس كل شيء في الماضي♪
♪The words were similar♪
♪الكلمات كانت متشابهة♪
♪With eyes closed, it felt like you were right beside me♪
♪مع عيون مغلقة، شعرت وكأنك كنت بجانبي مباشرة♪
♪That moment I saw you, spring awakened in me♪
♪في تلك اللحظة التي رأيتك فيها، أيقظ الربيع في داخلي♪
♪My heart suddenly becomes soft and tender♪
♪قلبي فجأة يصبح رقيقًا وحنونًا♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪Smiles and tears blurred everything in the past♪
♪الابتسامات والدموع طمس كل شيء في الماضي♪
♪The words were similar♪
♪الكلمات كانت متشابهة♪
♪With eyes closed, it felt like you were right beside me♪
♪مع عيون مغلقة، شعرت وكأنك كنت بجانبي مباشرة♪
♪After we part and meet again♪
♪بعد أن نفترق ونلتقي مرة أخرى♪
♪Your face had already changed♪
♪وجهك قد تغير بالفعل♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪If your words are clear♪
♪إذا كانت كلماتك واضحة♪
♪Like an image carved in the bones♪
♪مثل صورة منحوتة في العظام♪
♪It doesn't matter whose skin the soul hides underneath♪
♪لا يهم من يختبئ تحت جلد الروح♪